《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
这个御土师
This Earth-Bender has been spotted
出现在历史上多个犯罪现场
at the scene of the crime throughout history.
庞贝末日  甚至还有诺亚时期的洪水
Pompeii, even as far back as Noah's flood.
他就是能控制土地
He literally manipulates the Earth.
你下次不会再逃出我的掌心了  氪星人
You won't survive me again, Kryptonian.
不要啊  罗素  救命啊
No! No, Russ! Please, somebody help!
我甘愿与你联结  请求你的原谅
I beg your forgiveness by submitting myself to the bond.
他临终前告诉我你就是超女
With his dying breath, he told me that you were Supergirl.
你不断地向我保证  你永远不会骗我
You reassured me, ad nauseam, you would never lie to me.
然而一直以来
And all the while,
在我们的友谊中都没有一个诚实的时刻
there wasn't a single honest moment in our friendship.
请不要将大清洗带离堡垒
Please, don't leave the fortress with Myriad.
请不要因为我的错误而做坏事
Please don't let my mistake push you to do something terrible.
入侵者
Intruder!
我不是坏人
I'm not a villain.
你不该把我当成坏人对待
You shouldn't have treated me like one.
卡拉
Kara.
是堡垒的防御
It's the Fortress's defenses.
有人用它来对付超女
Someone's turned them against Supergirl.
我们无法用通讯器联络到你
We couldn't reach you on comms.
出什么事了  你没事吧
What happened? Are you all right?
我跟着罗摩·可汗的能量踪迹到了这里
I traced Rama Khan's energy trail here.
-我必须找到莉娜  -罗摩·可汗做了什么
- I have to find Lena. - What did Rama Khan do?
不是他  是莉娜  她知道了
It wasn't him. It was Lena. She knew.
她知道什么
She knew what?
知道了我的身份  她已经知道了几个月
My identity. She's known for months.
是莱克斯告诉她的  她因此恨我
Lex told her, and she hates me for it.
莉娜在诺奎山
Lena's in Mount Norquay.
诺奎山是莱克斯的其中一个老巢
Mount Norquay is one of Lex's old hideouts.
-你要去哪里  -收拾残局
- Where are you going? - To fix this.
诺奎山
让大清洗上线运行
Get Myriad online and operational.
还有几个小时  无害计划就要开始了
Non Nocere launches within the hour.
霍普  准备工作很出色
And, Hope, excellent work preparing the move.
我们的Q波发生器已经准备好与大清洗合并
Our Q-wave generator is ready to integrate with Myriad.
超女
Supergirl?
已侦测到氪星X光视线
别担心  地堡已铅封  她找不到我们的
Don't worry. The bunker's lead-lined. She can't find us.
正在植入装置
这些是莱克斯的装置
These are Lex's countermeasures.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
卢瑟女士
Ms. Luthor?
部署
Deploy.
离子射线大炮已装载
这样应该能牵制住她
That should keep her at bay.
安全警报
终止操作失败
又怎么了
What's happening now?
似乎在用氪石重新武装大炮
It appears to be re-arming the cannons with Kryptonite.
-取消  -现在是自动操作
- Cancel it. - It's on an automatic override.
安全警报
氪石大炮已装载
错误代码
-快关闭  -没有反应
- Shut it down. - It's not responding.
立刻关闭
Shut it down now!
莉娜  别这么做
Lena, don't... don't do this.
系统自动操作
大炮已解除
我们必须忠于我们的使命
We must stay true to our mission.
不管他们如何伤害我们  都不能杀人
We don't kill people... no matter how much they've hurt us.
我是不会放弃你的
I'm not gonna give up on you.
超 女
第五季 第八集
怎么了
What happened?
超女和卢瑟怎么又打败你了
How did Supergirl and Luther beat you again?
过程不重要
It doesn't matter how.
我只是要和她解释
I just need to explain to her.
要是我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that.
人们都在议论你
They're whispering about you.
说你丧失了锋芒
That you've lost your edge.
地震造不成伤亡
Earthquakes with no death counts,
洪水就如漏水的水龙头一般微弱
floods with the ferocity of a leaky faucet.
他们说长者也许会让德苏马克来掌管
They're saying that the Elder may put Tezumak in charge.
德苏马克
Tezumak?
他的战争策略毫无下限
His tactic of war is without limits.
他有可能会不小心把地球夷为平地
He could accidentally burn down the earth.
我同意
I agree.
我已经掌管了两百万年
I have been in charge for two million years.
但是你最近迷失了
And you've been losing lately,
他会以此来对付你
and he'll hold that against you.
德苏马克狡猾如蛇
Tezumak is a snake.
我猜猜  接下来你要建议我说
Oh, and let me guess. Next is your advice
你的方法更有效
about how your way is so much more efficient.
在这里操纵人心的不止德苏马克一人
Tezumak isn't the only manipulator around here.
我昨天说的话有欠公允
Look, what I said yesterday was unfair.
没错  我相信我的技术能成功
Yes, I believe my technology would work.
但是我也同意
But I agree.
你的方法更有效
Your way is more efficient.
这和自负没关系  罗摩·可汗
This isn't about ego, Rama Khan.
而是关乎拯救地球
It's about saving the earth.
世界正处在崩塌点  没有回头路了
The world is at a tipping point. There's no turning back.
人类会毁灭这个星球  除非我们先将人类毁灭
The humans will destroy this planet unless we destroy them first.
但要怎么做
But how?
氪星人是不会罢手的
The Kryptonian won't stop.
她誓死都会保护这些人类
She will die to protect these humans.
那就让超女去死吧
Then let Supergirl die trying.
这是近两千年来
The planets are coming into alignment
行星首次排成一线
for the first time in nearly 2,000 years.
但是只在今晚
But only for tonight.
上次排成一线时  我摧毁了庞贝
The last time this happened, I wiped out Pompeii.
值得重复的杰作
A masterpiece worth repeating.
恕我直言
If a little on the blunt side.
就算是超女也无法阻止大规模火山爆发
Not even Supergirl can stop a massive volcano.
没有坠子
The Staff of the Shadow World
暗影世界之杖就毫无价值可言
is worthless without the Medallion.
你需要的是坠子的力量  而不是坠子本身
You need the Medallion's power, not the Medallion itself.
而你知道这力量是什么
And you know where that power is.
阿珂拉塔
Acrata.
超女  你找到莉娜了吗
Supergirl. Hey, did you find Lena?
她去莱克斯的地堡干什么
What was she doing in Lex's bunker?
布莱尼  能在诺奎山脉下4.9公里范围内
Brainy, can you get some line of communication to a bunker
找到通讯线路吗
three miles below the Norquay mountain range?
能  但要取决于信号处理能力
Yes, but depending on the processing power--
好了  先停下  现在告诉我
Okay, stop. Just tell me right now,
莱克斯是什么时候把你的身份告诉莉娜的
when did Lex tell Lena your identity?
她为什么在孤独堡垒里攻击你
And why was she attacking you in the Fortress?
-到底是怎么回事  -那是雪莱岛之后的事
- What the hell is going on? - It was after Shelley Island.
-但莱克斯死在那里了  -他没死
- But Lex died there. - No, he didn't.
他穿越到了一个安全屋  莉娜开枪打死他了
He portaled somehow to a safe house where Lena shot him.
为了保护我  保护我们  她杀了他
She killed him to protect me, to protect all of us.
但在他死之前  他告诉她了
But before he died, he told her.
她一直骗了我们几个月
She's been lying to us for months.
那为什么现在才攻击你呢
Okay, so why attack you now?
这样她就能从孤独堡垒里偷走大清洗
So she could steal Myriad from the Fortress.
莉娜偷走了大清洗
Lena stole Myriad?
我就是这样追踪她到了诺奎山
It's how I tracked her to Norquay,
但我认为事情不是这样
but I don't think this is what it looks like.
她在孤独堡垒里  从摩罗·可汗手上救了我
She saved me from Rama Khan in the Fortress.
就算在莱克斯的地堡里
And even at Lex's bunker,
大炮上装满了氪石  但她也没拿来对付我
the cannons were loaded with Kryptonite, but she didn't use them.
我还可以修补我们的关系
I can still fix this.
如果我可以和她谈谈  我就可以说动她
I can get through to her, if I could just talk to her.
布莱尼  你能让我进去吗
Brainy, can you get me in there?
我们可以利用现有的氪星水晶
We could harness the Kryptonian cache crystals we have here
悄悄地向她的地堡发射全息图
to covertly project a hologram beam into her bunker.
-很好  -如果不是为了控制人口
- Great. - Okay, if not for mind control over the population,
那莉娜为什么需要大清洗
then why would Lena need Myriad?
我应该知道原因
I think I might know.
马拉法克
Malefic.
启动精神力抑制器
Engage Psychic Inhibitors.
艾丽克斯  别这样
Alex, please.
多克斯特工  逮捕疑犯
Agent Dox, apprehend the suspect.
艾丽克斯  别这样
Alex, please!
我和马拉法克已经心灵融合了
Malefic and I mind-melded.
我知道他真正的目的  他真是来帮忙的
I know his true intentions. He is here to help.
他有一些关于...
He has some information...
莉娜的信息
about Lena.
我曾是她的囚犯
I was her prisoner.
首先  你是怎么从幻影地带逃出来的
Okay, first, how did you escape the Phantom Zone?
我没逃  因为我从来都没去过那儿
I didn't escape. I was never there.
当幻影地带投射器在天文馆击中我时
When the Phantom Zone Projector hit me at the planetarium,
我直接去了卢瑟女士的实验室
I went directly to Ms. Luthor's lab.
是莉娜帮布莱尼修好了幻影地带投射器
Lena was the one who helped Brainy fix the Phantom Zone Projector.
她一定更改了终点坐标
She must have changed the end coordinates.
但她为什么需要你
But what did she need you for?
精神控制
Mind control.
她在拿我的植入能力做实验
She was experimenting with my ability to incept.
如果莉娜能利用马拉法克的Q波
If Lena can harness Malefic's Q-waves
并将其与大清洗的分配能力相结合
and merge them with the power of Myriad's distribution,
将产生前所未有的结果
the results would be unprecedented.
瞬间实现世界范围内的彻底控制
World-wide total control in an instant.
但我们还不知道她的意图
But we don't know her intentions.
她想削弱人类的暴力程度
She's trying to make people less violent.
利用大清洗是为了
You use Myriad to impose
将自己的意志强加给世界人口  而非拯救他们
your will on the world population, not save it.
她心里很受伤
She's hurting.
她经历的净是人类间的互相伤害
All she's experienced are people hurting each other,
像我一样
the same way I did.
-显然她认为自己在做好事  -确实如此
- Clearly, she thinks she's doing good. - It's true.
我早就想杀了我哥哥
I had long planned to destroy my brother,
但卢瑟女士说这违反了她的道德准则  并阻止了我
but Ms. Luthor said it went against her morality and stopped me.
艾丽克斯  她不会伤害任何人
Alex, she's not hurting anyone.
连她的囚犯马拉法克都没有伤害
Not even Malefic, her prisoner.
我还可以拯救她
I can still save her.
-这可说不准  -一定可以
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
是我伤害了她  所以要由我来弥补
I'm the one who hurt her, so I'm going to fix this.
布莱尼  发射全息图
Brainy, get the hologram online.
阿珂拉塔
Acrata.
-我有个任务交给你  -我也有任务给你
- I have a job for you. - And I have one for you.
你可以告诉他们
You can tell them to stop
不要再派你这样的特工来给我安排任务了
sending agents like you with jobs for me.
利维坦对我造成了巨大的伤害和损失
After everything Leviathan has done to me, taken from me...
告诉他们  我要退出
you can tell them that I quit.
-你是谁  -我是谁
- What are you? - What am I?
我是罗摩·可汗  这个地球的守护者
I am Rama Khan, guardian of this Earth,
正是我赋予了你能力
the one who endowed you with your powers.
我理解失去亲人的痛苦
I understand the pain of loss.
听我的话  我就给你一条出路
Obey me and I will offer you a way out.
告诉我你想要什么
Tell me what you want.
完成最后一项任务  你就自由了
One last job, then you will be released.
那我父亲呢
And my father?
你父亲可以保留他的财富
Your father can keep his riches.
它们价值甚微
For what little they're worth.
全息图已上线  准备开始
Hologram online and ready to commence.
祝你好运
Good luck.
就快好了  卢瑟女士
It's almost ready, Ms. Luthor.
我们只有一步之遥  霍普
We are so close, Hope.
我将完成数据合并
I'll finish consolidating the data.
我们可以拯救他们
We can save them.
他们所有人
All of them.
莉娜
Lena.
超女
Supergirl.
-求你听我说完  -省省力气吧
- Please, just hear me out. - Save your breath.
你让看到了你的真面目  我相信你
You showed me who you really are, and I believe you.
你有权利这么说  但请不要这么做
You have every right to say that, but don't do this.
做什么
Do what?
就是你打算用大清洗
Whatever it is you're planning
和马拉法克的Q波所采取的那项行动
on doing with Myriad and Malefic's Q-waves.
你有想过
Did it ever occur to you
我这是要为世界做件好事吗
that I was gonna do something good for the world?
用了大清洗  人们不会理解你的
With Myriad, people won't understand.
你当然会做最坏的设想  我不是坏人
Of course, you assumed the worst. I'm not the bad guy.
我知道  你花了几年时间想要敞开心扉  学会信任
I know. You spent years trying to be open and trusting,
即使所有人都认为你会像你的家人一样邪恶
even when everyone expected you to be like your family.
即使你生活中的每个人都让你失望
Even when everyone in your life let you down.
即使当我很软弱  对你撒谎
Even when I was weak and lied to you,
知道你想要的不过是真相
knowing that all you ever asked for was the truth,
你总能做个更好的人
you were always better.
莱克斯利用了我的弱点
Lex took advantage of my weakness
他用它来操纵你
and he used it to manipulate you.
他希望我的错误能够改变你
He wanted my mistakes to change you.
他希望你成为他
He wanted you to become him.
但你一点也不像他
But you are nothing like him.
一点也不像
Nothing.
不要因为我的错误而改变自己
Don't let my mistakes turn you into something you're not.
我是好人
I am good.
我一直都是
And I always was.
莱克斯没改变我  你也没改变我
Lex didn't change me and you didn't change me either.
你让我见识了人性的丑陋
You just exposed me to the ugliness of humanity.
你帮了我个忙  卡拉
You did me a favor, Kara.
我了解了你到底是个怎样的骗子
I learned what kind of deceitful person you really are,
正是这一点启发了我去做这件事
and that's what inspired me to do this.
-莉娜  -你的话对我已经没有意义了
- Lena-- - Your words mean nothing to me anymore.
别洒狗血了  不要打扰我
Spare us both the drama. Leave me alone.
等等
Wait.
你还好吗
You okay?
不好
No.
我说服不了她
I couldn't get through to her.
抱歉
Sorry.
在我的意识里
You know, a part of me
我一直知道这并不容易
always knew that this couldn't be that easy.
我明白  我完全理解她为何会有被背叛的感觉
And I get it. I fully understand why she feels betrayed.
她很难相信别人
It's so hard for her to trust people.
但我让她相信了我
But I made her trust me.
一次又一次  我让她相信
Over and over again, I made her believe
我是永远不会伤害她的最好的朋友
that I was the best friend who would never ever hurt her.
然后她以最可怕的方式发现
And then she finds out in the most horrible way
我们的友谊建立在谎言上
that our entire friendship was based on lies.
你告不告诉她都会是这个下场  卡拉
Look, you were damned either way, Kara.
你选择隐藏你的身份
Your choice to conceal your identity,
这并非出于恶意
it wasn't born out of a place of maliciousness.
而是源于爱和同情
It was born out of love and compassion.
你只是想保护你的家人
And you were just trying to protect your family.
你是想保护莉娜
And you were trying to protect Lena
不被利用这些信息的恶人所伤害
from people who could use that information to hurt us.
我也爱莉娜
And look, I love Lena, too.
这件事让我深感不安
I am deeply upset by what is going on.
可是这...
But this...
这不仅仅是两个朋友在打架
This isn't just two friends that are in a fight.
她已经走上了不归路
This is someone who has turned a corner.
不  这不是真正的她  这不是我们的莉娜
No, but this is not her. This is not our Lena.
那谁才是我们的莉娜  我是说
Well, who is our Lena? I mean...
她知道莱克斯出狱了  但却选择沉默
She knew that Lex was out of prison, and she said nothing.
她把小萨·阿里亚斯关在L公司的地下室里
She kept Sam Arias locked in a subbasement at L-Corp,
知道她就是主宰  但却缄口不言
knowing that she was Reign, and she said nothing.
她知道怎么做氪石
She knows how to make Kryptonite,
但却一直瞒着我们
and she kept that hidden from us.
莉娜过着双重生活
Lena is leading her own double-life.
你说得她好像是卢瑟家的人
You are making her sound like a Luthor.
因为她本来就是
Maybe that's because she is one.
我们不能寄希望于
We can't put our faith in some distant hope
她会做出正确的事
that she's gonna do the right thing...
因为到目前为止
...when every single action
她所做的每一件事都指向邪恶
that she has taken up until now points to the contrary.
我们得阻止她  卡拉
Okay, we have to stop her, Kara.
这事关世界的安全
The safety of the world depends on that.
她不是莱克斯  我不会把她当恶棍看待
She is not Lex. I will not treat her like a villain.
我知道你不会  所以这事才要交给我来做
I know you won't. That's why I have to.
你这是什么意思
What are you talking about?
你跟她通话的时候  我们利用全息图
When you went to speak to her, we used the hologram
将病毒植入了地堡的主机
to piggyback a virus into the bunker's mainframe.
艾丽克斯  你利用了我
Alex, you used me?
过一会儿  莉娜的防线就会被攻破
In a few moments, Lena's defenses will be down
大清洗将陷入停滞
and Myriad will be stalled.
到时候  如果我们不得不采取更激烈的措施
By then, if we have to take more drastic actions,
克莱莫3号已部署在了诺奎山上
Claymore 3 is positioned above Mount Norquay.
-什么  -我会给她时间投降
- What? - And I will give her time to surrender.
卡拉  我必须开始动脑思考了
Kara, we have to start thinking with our heads,
不能感情用事
not with our hearts.
准备好了  卢瑟女士
It's ready, Ms. Luthor.
超女给你带来了巨大的痛苦
Supergirl caused you a great deal of pain.
我能从你的眼神中看出来
I can see it in your eyes.
经历了我家人和安德里亚的事
After my family and after Andrea,
我本应学会不再信任友谊
I knew better than to trust in friendship anymore.
你现在经历着这么多痛苦
All of the anguish that you're going through,
感觉并不值得
it doesn't seem worth it.
它启发了"无害"计划
It inspired Non Nocere.
也启发了你
It inspired you.
如果能拯救世界  谁还需要朋友
Who needs friends when you can save the world?
准备发射
大清洗可以发射了
Myriad is ready to launch.
卢瑟女士  你的时刻到了
Ms. Luthor, this is your moment.
要启动吗
Shall I activate?
-三  二  -一
- Three, two... - One.
连接失败
怎么回事
What's happening?
一直跟卫星对接不了
It won't lock onto the satellite.
有东西干扰了接收天线的移动能力
Something's interfering with the dishes' ability to move.
是一种病毒  正在入侵主机
It's a virus. It's working through our mainframe.
卢瑟女士  那个全息图
Ms. Luthor, the hologram.
是特洛伊木马病毒  原来如此
It was a Trojan horse. Of course.
我怎么能幼稚到觉得超女是想跟我聊聊
How could I be so naive to think that Supergirl wanted to talk?
如果病毒扩散  超查部能够在20分钟内
If the virus spreads, the DEO will be able to deactivate
关闭我们的安防系统
our security defenses in 20 minutes.
在那之前我们需要想到变通方案
We need a workaround before then.
我们可以手动解锁波段
We could manually unlock the arrays.
不行  这里到处都是莱克斯设下的饵雷
No, Lex has booby-trapped this entire place.
如果我尝试更改天线  会启动致命的故障保险
There'll be a lethal failsafe if I try to tamper with the dishes.
那我去
Then I'll go.
不行
No, you can't.
你太珍贵了
You're too great an asset.
卢瑟女士  你当初为我设定的最重要的任务之一
Ms. Luthor, one of my prime directives, as you programmed,
就是保证"无害"计划的成功
was to ensure the success of Non Nocere.
如果这意味着牺牲自己
If that means self-sacrifice--
不行  就算能手动重置
No. Even if you could manually reset it,
也没办法确认病毒造成了多少伤害
there's no telling the extent of the virus's damage.
我们以后还需要你
All right, we may need you.
如果现在失去你  就太目光短浅了
It'd be short-sighted to lose you now.
如果我们能复制病毒
If we could replicate the virus,
就可以反向编程
we could reverse-engineer it
远程覆写之前的关闭指令
and override the shutoff remotely, okay?
我需要你的帮助
I'll need some help.
好的
Very well.
正在读取文件
Accessing files.
荣恩  你不需要留在这里
J'onn, you don't need to stay here.
我应该被关起来
I deserve to be locked up.
我们应该共同承担
We both shoulder the blame
过去所作所为的后果  马拉法克
for the transgressions of our past, Malefic,
但是只要携手  我们能克服过去
but together, we will move beyond them.
-荣恩  荣恩  -怎么了
- J'onn, J'onn. - What's up?
艾丽克斯  她认为莉娜已经无药可救了
Alex, she thinks Lena is past the point of no return.
她已经让克莱莫3号直指地堡
She's got Claymore 3 pointed directly at the bunker.
但你可以劝劝她  对吗  让她知道自己错了
But you can talk to her, right? Show her that she's wrong?
你知道人是可以变的  看看你和马拉法克
You know people can change. Look at you and Malefic.
我能救莉娜  我只是需要时间
I can still save Lena. I just need more time.
在火星时  我经历过艾丽克斯如今的处境
I was in Alex's position back on Mars
当时我选择将马拉法克逐入幻影地带
when I banished Malefic to the Phantom Zone.
我以为我这样做是在保护我的族人
I did so because I thought I was protecting my people.
但我驱逐他其实是因为自己害怕
But I banished him because I was afraid,
因为没有其他选择
because there was no other way.
可是看看你们如今的情况
Right, and look at the two of you now.
我和马拉法克之所以能够
The only reason Malefic and I were able to
重新放下过去的一切
come through the other side
是因为我们能看到彼此的痛苦
is because we can see each other's pain.
而你已经跟莉娜聊过了
You've already talked to Lena.
我不是说艾丽克斯说得对
I'm not saying Alex is right,
但她似乎也没有其他选择
but what other option does she have?
不  一定有其他的方式能阻止她
No. There has got to be another way to stop Lena
而不是把她从地堡里炸飞
that isn't blowing her up in a bunker.
马拉法克
Malefic.
马拉法克  你说莉娜之前在分析你的Q波
Malefic, you said Lena was analyzing your Q-waves, right?
对
Yes.
她分离出了某个频段
She isolated a frequency
让她能够复制我的能力
which allowed her to replicate my ability.
也许你就是关键
Maybe you're the key.
如果我们能够驾驭你的Q波
If we could harness your Q-waves--
就能够用它来拦截莉娜的
We could use them to counteract Lena's.
可她要发起全球范围内的攻击
But she's launching a worldwide attack.
马拉法克用来拦截她所需的能量...
The amount of energy Malefic would need to counteract hers...
会害死他的
It could kill him.
值得冒这个险
It's worth the risk.
不  我不要以命换命
No, I am not trading one life for another.
求你了
Please.
如果我能阻止卢瑟女士犯下我当年的错误
If I can stop Ms. Luthor from making the same mistakes that I did,
那我所造成的那些痛苦和动荡
then all of the turmoil and pain that I've caused
就不算枉费
will be worth something.
让我帮忙吧
Let me help.
让我做些补偿吧
Let me make amends.
超级火山
目标是谁
Who's the target?
就是你面前的这一切
You're looking at it.
超级火山为何物? 它会如何爆发?
超级火山
A supervolcano?
你不是在开玩笑吧
No. You can't be serious.
你会把他们都杀死的
You'd be killing all of them.
从世界诞生之时起  就不断上演着
Extinction level events have been happening
灭绝性的事件
since the beginning of time.
我很清楚
I should know.
我是来促成这一切的
I was here to make them happen.
这些人做了什么  要被如此对待
What have these people done to deserve this?
存在即有罪
Existence is their sin.
别认为这是终点
Don't think of this as the end.
这是在给世界一次新的机会
Think of this as giving the world a second chance.
我为你工作了这么多年
For years I've worked for you,
一直告诉自己这是为了公平正义
telling myself there was a just cause.
够了
No more.
也许我不能打败你
Maybe I can't beat you...
但你认为超女做不到吗
but you don't think Supergirl will?
超女不是神  我才是
Supergirl is not a god. I am!
-怎么了  -外围出现了漏洞
- What's going on? - There's been a perimeter breach.
-有具体位置吗  -没有
- Do we have a location? - Negative.
救命  罗摩·可汗要来了  他要摧毁世界
Help! Rama Khan is coming. He's gonna destroy the world
蠢材
You fool.
我是要拯救这个星球
I'm saving this planet.
我将重塑地球
Now I will remake the earth,
正如我很久之前应该做的
as I should have done a long time ago.
你不能亲眼见识  真是遗憾
It's a pity you won't be here to see it.
但利维坦感谢你的帮助
But Leviathan thanks you for your service.
布莱尼  跟我说一下情况
Brainy, I need a status update.
地堡安保系统还有11分钟关闭
Eleven minutes until the bunker's defenses are down.
-艾丽克斯  地堡的事...  -罗摩·可汗呢
- Alex, about the bunker-- - And Rama Khan?
我分析了影子出现的安保录像
I've analyzed security footage of the appearance of the Shadow
以及她携带的物品
and of the object she was carrying.
叫作"影子世界的魔杖"
It's called "The Staff of the Shadow World."
它是古美索不达米亚人创造的
It is an artifact associated with ancient Mesopotamians,
但在赫库兰尼姆城也能找到
but can also be found in Herculaneum.
我把我们的图片和罗摩·可汗的照片进行比对
I juxtaposed our image with historical images
你们看
of Rama Khan and voila.
他们上次被人看到是在庞培古城
The two were last seen in the ancient city-state of Pompeii.
-真令人不安  -是啊
- That's concerning. - Indeed.
尤其是那件魔杖散发出的能量
Especially as it seems the energy given off by the Staff
在纳欣诺市另一个地方也出现了
can be found in one other place in National City.
就是我们推测出利维坦藏身的大楼
The building where we assumed Leviathan was hiding.
利维坦
就在沥青坑街对面
That's across the street from the Tar Pits.
也是休眠超级火山的所在地
Also the site of a dormant supervolcano.
上次喷发是在新生代早期
The last eruption was in the early Cenozoic Era,
比庞培古城的火山喷发强一万倍
and was 10,000 times more powerful than Pompeii.
罗摩·可汗是个御土师
Rama Khan's an Earth-Bender.
他是想在纳欣诺市重现庞培灾难
So he's trying to recreate Pompeii in National City.
-一万倍的庞培灾难  -好吧
- Pompeii times 10,000. - Okay.
我们得逐个击破
We need to divide and conquer.
超女  荣恩  你们去沥青坑
Supergirl, J'onn, I want you to get to the Tar Pits,
找到罗摩·可汗  阻止他
find Rama Khan and stop him.
你说上一次音速炮打败了他
You said the Sonic Cannon defeated him the last time,
那就去孤独堡垒拿来
so go to the Fortress and get that.
-布莱尼  我需要更新下  -艾丽克斯  等下
- Brainy, I need an update on-- - Alex, wait.
我有事情要告诉你  你不需要克莱莫
I have to tell you something. You don't have to use Claymore.
我们认为可以用马拉法克的Q波来抵消莉娜的
We think we can use Malefic's Q-waves to counteract Lena's,
阻止她用大清洗
stop her using Myriad.
理论上来说  他是对的
Theoretically, he is correct.
好吧  你想让我用一个已知的威胁
Okay, you want me to use a known threat
去阻止一个眼前的威胁吗
to stop an imminent one?
把全球Q波发射器交给一个恐怖分子
Handing over a global Q-wave projector to a terrorist?
要是马拉法克在被释放后就变了想法呢
What if Malefic just decides to change his mind once we free him?
-他改变了  -你不能确定
- He's changed. - But you don't know that for sure.
而且现在莉娜和罗摩·可汗想要重现庞贝灾难
And between Lena and Rama Khan gearing up for Pompeii 2.0,
我最不想要的就是第三个灾难
the last thing that I need is a third catastrophe.
我们没时间了  你得出发了
We are running out of time. You need to go.
艾丽克斯  求你  我知道你认为你是正确的
Alex, please. I know you think what you're doing is right,
但她是我们的朋友
but she is our friend.
如果你用了克莱莫  就没有回头路了
If you use Claymore, there's no turning back from that.
我去拿炮  在焦油坑和你们会面
I'll get the Cannon. I'll meet you at the Tar Pits.
她不理解这对我来说有多难
She doesn't understand how hard this is for me.
我是说  莉娜也是我的朋友
I mean, Lena is my friend, too,
现在突然间  我就要决定
and now all of a sudden, I'm supposed to decide
是不是要冒着其他所有人的生命危险去救她
whether I should risk everybody's lives just to save hers?
还有马拉法克  他入侵了我的思想
And Malefic, he invaded my mind.
他威胁了凯莉  难道还要我相信他
He threatened Kelly, and now I'm just supposed to trust him?
你知道这事关紧要
You know what's on the line.
是你教会我如何做这个工作的
You're the one who taught me how to do this job,
是你做出那些艰难的决定
and you're the one who's had to make really tough decisions
来保证没有人丧命
so that people don't die.
你完全有理由害怕我的弟弟
You have every reason to fear my brother.
我不能向你保证马拉法克绝对变好了
I can't promise you that Malefic has changed for good.
人们会犯错然后做出可怕的事情
People make mistakes and they do terrible things.
我们要给他们机会改过
We have to let them do better,
让他们回到光明下
bring them back into the light.
不然
Otherwise...
拯救所有人还有什么意义
what's the point in trying to save everyone?
超查部送来了另一个警告
The DEO has sent another warning.
九分钟后  我们的防卫就会失效
In nine minutes, our defenses will be disabled.
-你需不需要我  -删掉
- Do you want me to-- - Delete it.
怎么回事
What was that?
感觉像是余震
That felt like a residual aftershock.
没错  一个5.4级的地震
Yes. A 5.4-magnitude earthquake
就在纳欣诺市中心
right in the heart of National City.
地震使整个天线阵下线了
It's knocked the entire satellite array offline.
我现在没办法做任何反向工程了
There's no way I can reverse-engineer anything now.
我可以试试用手动超控
I can still try a manual override.
我可以自己定位天线碟
I can reposition the dishes myself.
我们谈过这个  绝对不行
We discussed this. Absolutely not.
你可能会死  霍普和伊芙都会永远消失了
You could be killed. Both Hope and Eve gone, forever.
但这对我们俩都有好处  因为我相信你
But it would be worth it for both of us because I believe in you.
伊芙也是
Eve did, too.
我看到了人类的堕落
I have seen the depravity of humans.
背叛与痛苦
the betrayal and the pain.
让我帮忙  这样我们就能
Let me help, so that we can stop them
一劳永逸地阻止他们再做出那些恶行
from committing any more of these horrible acts once and for all.
不  我不允许  我们另寻他法
No. I will not allow it. We will find another way.
你的陪伴对我意义很大  霍普
Your partnership has meant the world to me, Hope.
你是我唯一可以指望的朋友
You're the only friend I can count on.
但是  卢瑟小姐  我不是你的朋友
But, Ms. Luthor, I'm not your friend.
我是你创造出来完成目标的
I'm something you created to serve a purpose.
你说得对
You're right.
只有一个办法
This is the only way.
你的物理扫描上有什么发现吗
Anything on your psychic scan?
什么都没有
Nothing.
布莱尼会不会搞错了
Could Brainy have been wrong?
显然没有
Apparently not.
他用的不仅是御土能力
He's using something more than earth-bending powers.
你说得对
You're right.
我看到暗影世界之杖在一个地下室里
I see the Shadow and the Staff in an underground chamber.
-看起来她被困住了  -交给我
- It looks like she's stuck. - I've got her.
莉娜有回应我们的警告吗
Has Lena responded to any of our warnings?
还没  她好像是删掉了它们
None so far. She appears to be deleting them.
她的自动防御系统将在五分钟后解除
Her auto defenses will be disabled in five minutes.
如果发射克莱莫发射  我们胜算有多大
If Claymore is launched, what are our odds?
百分之九十八几率大清洗被中和
98% chance Myriad will be neutralized
万分之一的几率莉娜会投降
and a .01% chance Lena will surrender,
也就是说莉娜几乎不会幸存
which makes it a virtual certainty Lena will not survive.
-如果我们用马拉法克呢  -几率微小变化
- And if we use Malefic? - Our odds shift slightly.
百分之八十六的几率阻止大清洗
86% chance we will stop Myriad
并且百分之零的几率
and a 0% chance
莉娜会受伤
Lena will be harmed.
锁定克莱莫  准备马拉法克
Lock Claymore in position, and prep Malefic.
但是布莱尼  告诉他哪怕是笑一下
But, Brainy, you let him know that if he so much as smiles,
我都会让几十名特工
I will have a dozen agents
将他们的枪指向他的心脏
and their guns pointed directly at his heart.
没用的
It's useless.
这杖支撑着我  它需要我
The Staff holds me and it needs me.
你们在一起会协助他的所作所为
Together you're fueling what he's doing.
我不会让这种事发生
I'm not gonna let that happen.
-我到了  卢瑟小姐  -好的  小心点
- I'm here, Ms. Luthor. - Okay, careful. Now,
在最近的天线碟底端  应该有接入面板
at the base of the nearest dish, there should be an access panel.
锁住了  键盘被装了爆炸装置
It's locked, and the keypad's rigged to blow.
该死  莱克斯
Damn it, Lex.
我们还剩三分钟
We only have three minutes.
好吧  这是一组瞄准天空的天线碟
Well, it's a group of satellite dishes aimed at the sky.
莱克斯喜欢象征
Lex loved symbolism.
也许密码与天堂有关系
Perhaps the code has something to do with Heaven.
-或是地狱  -约翰·密尔顿
- Or Hell. - John Milton.
莱克斯最喜欢的《失乐园》词句是什么
What was Lex's favorite quote from Paradise Lost?
"起来  否则永远沉沦"
"Arise or be forever fallen."
允许进入
成功了
It worked.
手动定位天线
Manually positioning the dishes.
海拔  14.9  方位  253.1
Elevation, 14.9. Azimuth, 253.1.
卢瑟小姐  我们已锁定并准备好发射大清洗
Ms. Luthor, we are locked and ready to launch Myriad.
真棒  霍普  你成功了
Amazing, Hope. You've done it.
现在  我也会
And now, so will I.
大清洗已发射
Myriad has launched!
毫无意外
Of course it has.
第一轮Q波到达地球还有30秒
We have 30 seconds until the first Q-waves reach Earth.
发射拦截
Launch the interception.
马拉法克的拦截起作用了
Malefic's intercept is working.
等下
Wait.
不不不
No, no, no.
不  没起作用
No, it's not working.
马拉法克的Q波能量输出
Malefic's Q-wave energy output
仅仅差那么一点就能阻止大清洗
is just shy of the power we need to stop Myriad.
我们有没有办法提升能量
Is there any way to up the power?
我们可以关闭能量抑制器
We can turn off our Psychic Inhibitors.
-别拿这个开玩笑  -我没开玩笑
- Don't even joke about that. - I'm not joking.
抑制器吸收百分之六的
The Inhibitors absorb 6% of
马拉法克能量输出  也就是四千太瓦
Malefic's energy output, or 4,000 terawatts.
如果我们要提升所需的百分之六
If we want to increase his power by the necessary 6%,
我们就需要移除
we have to remove the
抑制器的影响  基本算数
Inhibitors from the equation. It's basic math.
我不会让我的特工面临这样的风险
I will not expose my agents to that risk.
这是假设那是个风险
That assumes there is a risk.
约翰说他的弟弟改变了
J'onn said his brother has changed.
火山爆发还有两分钟
Two minutes until the volcano explodes,
而大清洗到达地球还有十秒
and ten seconds until Myriad reaches Earth.
我们是关掉抑制器还是激活克莱莫
Do we turn off our Inhibitors or do we activate Claymore?
七秒  局长  五秒  艾丽克斯
Seven seconds, Director. Five. Alex!
所有特工  立刻关闭抑制器
All agents, Inhibitors off, now.
发生了什么
What's happening?
看  你们这些超级英雄的毛病就是
See, that's the problem with you superheroes.
总是站在弱者的一边
You align yourselves with the weak.
你为那些人类作战
You fight for these humans,
但一次又一次
but time after time,
他们所作的就是破坏身边的一切
all they do is destroy everything around them.
你倒是有脸说
You're one to talk.
我承认  我也会破坏
Oh, I admit, I destroy.
用净化之火
But with a cleansing fire.
这是对付人类祸害的唯一办法
That's the only way to deal with the scourge of humanity.
我来地球几百万年了
I have been here for millions of years.
一直以来都是如此
It's how it's always been...
将来亦会是如此
and how it always will be.
超女
Supergirl?
你能听见我吗  马拉阻止了大清洗
Can you hear me? Mal stopped Myriad.
你和罗摩·可汗怎么样了
Where are you with Rama Khan?
你不明白吗
Don't you see?
人无法改变
People never change.
不  罗摩·可汗  你错了  人可以改变
No, Rama Khan. You're wrong. People can change.
正因如此  这个世界才这么美丽
That is what is so beautiful about this world.
你做到了
You did it.
-你阻止了火山喷发  -你击败了他
- You stopped the volcano. - You knocked his block off.
不
No!
他们阻止了大清洗  我不明白
They stopped Myriad. I don't understand.
没什么好不明白的
There's nothing to understand.
我输了
I lost.
这是一次人生教训
This is a life lesson to learn.
有时邪能胜正
Sometimes the good guys don't win.
够了
Enough.
结束了  罗摩·可汗
It's over, Rama Khan.
你在说什么  伽梅姆
What are you talking about, Gamemnae?
地球秩序尚存  我还有时间
The planets are still aligned. There's still time!
但你没有了
Not for you.
你没有时间了
Not anymore.
我仍然可以完成大业
I can still finish this.
你错失了最后一次机会  你的统治结束了
You've had your last go. Your reign is over.
她会对此颇有微词
She'll have something to say about this.
你以为是谁委任了我
Who do you think appointed me?
这还没结束
This is not over!
对不起我失败了
I'm sorry I failed.
我希望我能为你做更多的事  卢瑟女士
I wish there was more I could do for you, Ms. Luthor.
你可以
There is.
我明白了
I see.
别动
Don't move.
莉娜·卢瑟  举起双手
Lena Luthor? Hands in the air.
不是她  是我  我做了这一切
It wasn't her. It was me. I did all of it.
放下枪  你被包围了
Drop the gun. You're surrounded.
伊芙  求求你
Eve, please.
带走她
Take her away.
卢瑟女士  你没事吧
Ms. Luthor, you all right?
你没事吧
You okay?
我这周都得擦披风上的泥土了
I'm gonna be scraping mud out of my cape for a week.
不  我是说你怎么样
No, I mean, are you okay?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
Me neither.
当联调局逮捕莉娜时  伊芙·泰斯马克在那里
When the FBI went to arrest Lena, Eve Tessmacher was there.
她承认主使了整件事
She confessed to the whole thing.
有她冒充莉娜的证据  有主使整件事的证据
Had proof that she impersonated Lena. Had proof for all of it.
我倒是希望那是真的
I wish that were true.
我们阻止了了大清洗
Well, we recovered Myriad,
但你知道莉娜的
but you know Lena.
-她是不会放弃的  -我知道
- She's not gonna stop. - I know.
多亏你  她还活着
She's alive, thanks to you.
也多亏你
Well, and to you.
你救莉娜和马拉法克是正确的
I mean, you were right about saving Lena, and Malefic.
他改变了
He changed.
谢谢你信任他和我
Well, thank you for trusting him, and me.
你比我更有信念
You had a lot more faith about that than I did.
如果我们能拯救马拉法克的灵魂
Well, if we can save Malefic's soul...
我们或许也能拯救莉娜的
Maybe we can save Lena's.
但这得改天了
But that is for another day.
凯莉和我要去吃寿司  你来吗
Kelly and I are gonna get some sushi. You wanna join?
不  你们去吧
No, no, you go ahead.
好的
Okay.
对了  我叫安德里亚
I'm Andrea, by the way.
我知道  我是罗素·罗杰斯
Oh, I know. I'm Russell Rogers.
今晚见
See you tonight?
好的
Yes.
结束了
It's over.
我终于做了正确的事
I finally did the right thing.
但我很抱歉为时已晚
I'm just sorry that it's too late.
我希望自己能够拯救你
I wish I could have saved you.
你救了我们  马拉
You saved us, Mal.
但这怎能弥补我犯下的过错呢
But how can I ever make up for what I've done?
如果一切都不同就好了
If only things were different.
有办法的
There is a way.
我希望你见一个人
And there's someone I'd like you to meet.
她的名字叫梅根  她是我的朋友
Her name is M'gann. She's a friend of mine.
她是白火星人反抗军战士
And she's a White Martian resistance fighter.
你抵达后  她可以帮你
She can help you when you arrive.
不敢相信战火仍在延续
Can't believe the war still rages.
-我助长的战火  -但现在你可以回家
- The war that I helped fuel. - But you can go home now.
帮助清除延绵的战火
You can help extinguish those flames.
但如果我做不到呢
But what if I can't?
我不像你一样强大  荣恩
I'm not strong like you, J'onn.
-赫隆米尔从没给我一席之地  -这是你的职责
- H'ronmeer never had a role for me-- - This is your role.
你知道白火星人
You know the White Martians,
你了解他们  知道他们的想法
you understand them, you know how they think.
你可以向他们呼吁
You can appeal to them.
马拉法克  你可以给火星带来
Malefic, you can bring peace to Mars
数百年来的第一次和平
for the first time in hundreds of years.
我们可以重新开始
We can start anew.
你从来都不活在鄙视中  马拉法克
You were never meant to be the pariah, Malefic.
你注定是天选之人
You were meant to be the promise.
谢谢你  哥哥
Thank you, my brother.
我会努力让你骄傲
I will strive to make you proud.
终结我发起的战争
And to end what I helped start.
没有这个你可办不到
Not without this you won't.
不准有任何刮痕
Not a scratch on it.
我尽量
I'll do my best.
干得好  荣恩·荣兹
Well done, J'onn J'onzz.
-你通过了测试  -测试
- You passed the test. - Test?
是你把我弟弟从幻影区释放了出来
You released my brother from the Phantom Zone?
你把我弟弟带到了这里
You brought my brother here?
当我看见你在异世界战斗时
When I saw you fight in Elseworlds,
我看得出你是个优秀的战士
I could see that you were a great warrior,
但是却被过去侵蚀  这让你变得软弱
but one plagued by his past, and that made you vulnerable.
你以为是因为你离开了火星
You believed it was because you had left Mars,
但其实却是更意味深长的事情  荣恩
but it was something far, far greater, J'onn.
你的弟弟
Your brother.
但现在你已经坦然面对了你的恶魔
But now that you have faced those demons,
并逐渐知道你的弱点是你的长处
you have come to learn your vulnerabilities are your strengths.
你已经准备好了
And now you are ready.
准备好干什么
Ready for what?
一场危机
A crisis.
再次将军
Checkmate. Again.
你终于回来了
Finally, you've returned.
我不知道有没有人告诉过你
I don't know if anybody's told you this,
但这里的风水有点不顺
but the feng shui of this place is a bit stale.
我复活你是因为
I brought you back because
宇宙需要你这样的头脑
the universe will need a mind like yours.
总能将军的人吗
Someone who can checkmate anyone?
是时候完成你的使命了  莱克斯·卢瑟
The time has come for you to fulfill your destiny, Lex Luthor.
你终于可以成为你一直期盼的英雄了
You can now become the hero that you have longed to be.
我一直是英雄
I've always been the hero.
乐意帮忙
Happy to help.
但首先我们得谈谈我妹妹
But first, we have to discuss my sister.
中城
地球一
这么多年来  我周游世界
For so many years, I've travelled across worlds,
穿越平行宇宙  只为了做一件事
across the multi-verse, to do one thing.
杀了你
To kill you.
但是现在  我们在这里
And now, we're here.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
服从并重新开始你的生活
Submit and begin your life anew.
展现给我看
Show me.
知识就在你心中
The knowledge is within you.